## Joseph Kochevar

Mailing Address: 13764 NE 12th ST APT J201 Bellevue, WA 98005

Last Updated on 29th October 2019

# SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Early- to Mid- career mechanical engineer with a strong background in mechanical design, large assembly management, drafting, and structural analysis. Possesses multidisciplinary industry-level engineering experience and a demonstrated ability to perform in a multitude of roles with high levels of success.

### **EDUCATION**

### **OLIN COLLEGE**

BS IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING May 2016 | Needham, MA

Recipient of 4-year, 50% Olin Merit Scholarship Conc. in Entrepreneurship Cum. GPA: 3.75 / 4.0

### **COURSEWORK**

#### **ENGINEERING**

Principles of Engineering†
Mechanical Design
Thermodynamics†
Microfluidics
Mechanical and Aerospace Systems
Design For Manufacturing

#### **ENTREPRENEURSHIP**

The Entrepreneurial Initiative New Technology Ventures Intellectual Property and Patent Law (†: Returned as Course Assistant)

### **SKILLS**

#### **MECHANICAL**

PTC Creo • Windchill • Ansys Solidworks • Solidworks PDM AutoDesk Inventor • AutoCAD

#### **SOFTWARE**

MATLAB • COMSOL • Arduino Java • C • C++ • HTML • Python

#### **FABRICATION**

Mill • Lathe • CNC • Laser Cutter Waterjet • 3d Printing • Vinyl Cutter Pneumatic Tools • Tube Bending MIG Welding • Brazing

### **EXPERIENCE**

### **BLUE ORIGIN** | PROPULSION ENGINEER II June 2016 - Present | Kent, WA

- Responsible engineer for BE-4 engine ancillary systems and secondary structure
- Primary configuration data manager for BE-4 engine assembly
- Configured multiple unique development engine builds to accommodate multiple stages of development and qualification testing
- Analyzed and released hundreds of drawings for development, qualification, and production
- Worked with external and internal customers to accommodate vehicle needs and manage system interfaces.
- Designed laser optics and purge tooling for custom manufacturing systems.

### **SENIOR CAPSTONE: BOEING** | MECHANICAL ENGINEER Sept 2015 - May 2016 | Needham, MA

- Optimized 737 final manufacturing to improve cargo bay panel installation.
- Also acting as business manager, organizing budgeting and purchases.

### **OLIN COLLEGE BLIND SAILING** | MECHANICAL ENGINEER June 2015 - Aug 2015 | Needham, MA

• Led mechanical design to outfit a sailboat with equipment to enable it to be sailed competitively by blind sailors.

### PROTEDYNE CORPORATION | MECHANICAL ENGINEERING INTERN June 2014 - Aug 2014 | Windsor, CT

- Assisted in design and modification of large-scale laboratory automation systems.
- Manipulated and created drawings, parts, and assemblies using SolidWorks.

### INTUIT: QUICKBASE | PD ENGINEERING INTERN, PRIVATE CONTRACTOR June 2013 – March 2014 | Waltham, MA

- Worked as a full-time engineer on the QuickBase Delight Product engineering team.
- Answered customer feedback, and added features to the automated email system.

### ATK AEROSPACE SYSTEMS | ENGINEERING INTERN

June 2012 - Aug 2012 | Monterey, CA

• Worked with a team of engineers on UAV sensing payload modules and advanced signal processing.

### LEADERSHIP AND ACTIVITIES

### **OLIN BAJA SAE** | TEAM CAPTAIN - DESIGN LEAD Aug 2012 - Present | Needham, MA

- Directed component- and system-level designs for four separate off-road racing vehicles.
- All designs used CAD modeling in SolidWorks, and finite element analysis to meet FS standards.

### ROBOTIC GUITAR Oct 2013 - May 2015

• Acted as the mechanical lead in the design and construction of a self-playing guitar system.

### CVT TESTING AND TUNING PLATFORM Oct 2012 - June 2016

- Designed and built platform to simulate, test, and tune Continuously Variable Transmissions.
- Created and modified simulations to predict and explain CVT performance.
- Made Olin Baja one of the first and only SAE Baja teams to have a full CVT simulation, testing, and diagnostic tool suite.